<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Select * from Languages</title><link href="http://www.selectstarfromlanguages.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.selectstarfromlanguages.com/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.selectstarfromlanguages.com/</id><updated>2015-03-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Plan of attack for learning French</title><link href="http://www.selectstarfromlanguages.com/how_im_learning_french.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Sara Thurman</name></author><id>tag:www.selectstarfromlanguages.com,2015-03-29:how_im_learning_french.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I want to share the resources I'm using to learn French. I started this a grand total of 5 days ago, so this isn't a review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fluent Forever&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main technique I'll be using is that outlined by Gabriel Wyner in his book and site &lt;a href="https://fluent-forever.com/"&gt;Fluent Forever&lt;/a&gt; (FF). The basic idea is that you first train your ears to hear your new language, then start learning a base vocabulary of 625 words using only pictures, no direct translation. From there you go on to grammar and making real, comprehensible sentences. All learning is based around using the spaced repetition learning technique, using the spaced repetition software (SRS) &lt;a href="http://ankisrs.net/"&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt;. Anki, aside from being free, is also open source and written in Python. I'll do a future post going into more detail, but if any of that is interesting to you, check out the &lt;a href="http://ankisrs.net/docs/addons.html"&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt; on creating add-ons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait a minute - why would you need to train your ears before diving into vocabulary? Because there are sounds you physically cannot hear currently! Your brain just can't distinguish them. And if you can't hear a certain sound, you certainly won't be able to make that sound when speaking. Not to mention the whole not being able to understand what other people are saying thing. Gabe goes into more detail in the book, and it's pretty interesting, at least to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the coolest parts about FF is that Gabe sells pronunciation trainers and professional audio recordings of all 625 words in the base word list, but he also tells you exactly how to do it yourself. And he does so on the site, not just the book. The book goes into more detail, but you don't &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to get it to know what to do. Benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The whole process can be totally free!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can create resources for a language FF doesn't cover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought the French pronunciation trainer and word list bundle. It was $20 and saves so much time. You can visit &lt;a href="https://fluent-forever.com/bundles/"&gt;the shop&lt;/a&gt; if you want to buy one too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Podcasts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be supplementing this primary training with a podcast or two. The podcasts aren't for memorizing any specific words or grammar rules, but just for listening to French spoken more naturally, not just the isolated words of initial vocab training. I've been testing a few out, and so far I've liked &lt;a href="http://www.learnfrenchbypodcast.com/"&gt;Learn French by Podcast&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://radiolingua.com/coffeebreakfrench/"&gt;Coffee Break French&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I am in no way affiliated with Fluent Forever, Learn French by Podcast, nor Coffee Break French.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://fluent-forever.com/"&gt;Fluent Forever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ankisrs.net/"&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.learnfrenchbypodcast.com/"&gt;Learn French by Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://radiolingua.com/coffeebreakfrench/"&gt;Coffee Break French&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="human language"></category><category term="french"></category><category term="anki"></category></entry></feed>